Atomic Veterans Records MS005
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Atomic Veterans Records
1942 -- 2006
1940 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Marlow, Sandra Kane
MS005
2.08 Linear Feet 2 half letter size document boxes, 1 letter size document box, 1 oversize box
2 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Subject Files and Reports; and Audiovisual Materials.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily contains secondary material donated by Sandra Marlow. Includes copies of several government publications and reports related to atomic testing and specific testing operations; subject files and news and research articles on topics including health effects, waste disposal, and nuclear energy; legal files relating to lawsuits on recognition and compensation for atomic veterans; congressional legislation on recognition and compensation for atomic veterans; one case from a veteran seeking recognition and compensation; and drafts of chapters from Barton C. Hacker's book, Elements of Controversy. The collection also includes Marlow's correspondence with veterans and their families, as well as correspondence with elected officials. Marlow's research materials, including articles, reports, and photocopies of archival materials are included in series one. Also included are thirteen photographic slides, and ten photographs (predominantly depicting veterans and their families), fifteen audio cassettes with veteran interviews, and six documentary videos.
Biographical / Historical
Sandra Kane Marlow was born on December 18, 1932 in New York City to Nicholas and Rose Kane, both Jewish immigrants from Europe. She has one younger sister, Stephanie. A "military brat," Kane moved with her family all over the United States while her father Colonel Kane was in the Air Force. He retired in 1955. Marlow graduated from Flushing High School, New York, in 1951 and graduated with a BA from Adelphi College, Garden City, New York, in 1955, as well as a MA in Art from U.C. Davis in 1965 and a Masters in Library Science (MLS) from University of Rhode Island in 1979.
Marlow married Harry C. Taylor and they had one daughter Alisa Taylor. From her second marriage with James Marlow she has a son, Benjamin Marlow. She worked as an art teacher in several schools in several states. After receiving her MLS, she worked as institutional librarian at Southeastern Correctional Center, an all-male prison in southeastern Massachusetts. Marlow fought for government acknowledgement and compensation of United States veterans that participated in atmospheric and underwater nuclear weapons tests and nuclear cleanup from 1945 until the Nuclear Test Ban in 1962.
When her father became ill from cancer in 1977, she began to search for answers about his exposure to nuclear explosives and illness and those of other veterans. Before he retired in 1955, he witnessed nuclear weapon tests at Camp Desert Rock, Nevada. Prior to that, in 1948, Colonel Nicholas Kane had been assigned to one of the first radiological safety courses at Treasure Island, California. He and other military personnel studied contaminated ships from the 1946 Pacific tests, called Operation Crossroads. In her quest, Marlow discovered other veterans and their families who had been exposed during the Cold War and learned that many others had a difficult time accessing information regarding exposure to nuclear weapons. Three years after her father died of leukemia in 1977, Marlow became an active member of the National Association of Atomic Veterans (NAAV) founded by Wanda and Orville Kelly. She served as its medical co-chair for many years.
Later, she joined the National Association of Radiation Survivors, another organization consisting of nuclear workers, uranium miners and civilians exposed to radiation. Living at that time in the Boston area, Marlow became their Academic Chair and communicated with members of the Federation of American Scientists as well as Doctors for Social Responsibility. With their help she helped organize a small group in the New England area called the Center for Atomic Radiation Studies (CARS). CARS members organized seminars at various universities and provided informational assistance to veterans and their families. They also helped publicize the problem of accessing information from the then Atomic Energy Commission and made the US public aware of the plight of "nuclear victims."
Marlow has testified before the US Senate on behalf of veterans' families. Along with members of NAAV and NARS, Marlow has persisted in obtaining government acknowledgement and compensation of American veterans that participated in atmospheric nuclear weapons tests and nuclear cleanup from 1945 until the Nuclear Test Ban in 1962. She has published articles in various journals including the Library Journal and the Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists. She has worked with investigative reporters on nuclear issues since 1977, including the contaminated nuclear ships brought to Treasure Island in 1948. Several of these journalists have won Pulitzer Prizes.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Marlow, Sandra Kane; National Association of Atomic Veterans; Nuclear weapons testing victims -- United States; Medical ethics; Human rights--United States.; Social justice; Greater Boston history
- Subject files and reports, 1940 -- 2012; MS005.001; 8.6 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains copies of several government publications and reports related to atomic testing and specific testing operations; subject files and news and research articles on topics including health effects, waste disposal, and nuclear energy; legal files relating to lawsuits on recognition and compensation for atomic veterans; congressional legislation on recognition and compensation for atomic veterans; one case from a veteran seeking recognition and compensation; and drafts of chapters from Barton C. Hacker's book, Elements of Controversy. The series also includes Marlow's correspondence with veterans and their families, as well as correspondence with elected officials. Marlow's research materials, including articles, reports, and photocopies of archival materials are included in series one.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Agent Orange Product Liability Litigation, 1983 -- 1984; MS005.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Arbeitsgemeinschaft Oekologischer Forschungsinstitute e.V., issue No. 5 including radiation measurements from August-September 1987 [Cooperative of Ecological Research Institutes], MS005.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Bikini: A Way of Life Lost William S. Ellis & James P. Blair National Geographic, 1986; MS005.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Center for Radiation Studies (CARS), including Questionnaire, Board Meeting Minutes, Guides for Veterans, Correspondene, and Press Releases, 1982 -- 1987; MS005.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Chernobyl, 1981 -- 1986; MS005.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Confuse and Deceive: The Great Nuclear Brainwash Independent Citizens Research Foundation for Study of Degenerative Diseases Inc., 1979; MS005.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Congress: Correspondence and Copies of Several Bills on Recognition and Compensation for Atomic Veterans, 1980 -- 1985; MS005.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Congress: Correspondence, Press Releases, Information Sheets, and Testimony Relating to Several Bills on Veterans Compensation, 1975 -- 1989; MS005.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Congress: Correspondence with Walter Lopes, Congressional Voting Records, 1982 -- 1986; MS005.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Congress: House and Senate Bills on Recognition, Compensation, and Health Care for Atomic Veterans, 1978 -- 1985; MS005.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Congress: H.R. 1338: Correspondence of MA Legislators, Congressional Publications, Petitions, and Information, 1983 -- 1987; MS005.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Congress: H.R. 1338: Testimony Scripts and Articles Relating to Bill, 1985; MS005.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Congress: Judiciary Testimony and Articles Relating to H.R. 1338, 1985; MS005.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Congress: Testimony of Sandra K. Marlow, Unknown Bill or Date, 1980 -- 1989; MS005.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Congress: Transcript of Testimony, DNA Fact Sheets, and Materials Relating to H.R. 1338 and Other Bills, 1980 -- 1985; MS005.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Committee Hearings Index of 1935-62, 1959 -- 1962; MS005.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Records, 1984; MS005.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Defense Civil Preparedness Agency: Publications - Federal and MA, 1968 -- 1978; MS005.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Defense Civil Preparedness Agency: Teacher's Manual for Your Chance to Live, 1972; MS005.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Defense Nuclear Agency: Fact Sheets, 1980 -- 1982; MS005.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Defense Nuclear Agency: Secrecy and Improper Science in Atomic Veteran Studies, Philip H. Melanson [Lopes, Walter Interview], 1984; MS005.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Disaster Nursing Frances Crouch Nabbe Littlefield, Adams & Co. Nurse's Handbook Series, 1961; MS005.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Edgerton, Gerneshausen & Grier Inc.: A Decade of Pioneering [EGG I 1984], 1958; MS005.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - The Effects of High-Yield Nuclear Explosions [History II: 1957 Gov't Report] U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1955; MS005.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Energy: Articles, 1979 -- 1980; MS005.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Energy: Facing Up to the Problem, Getting Down to Solutions National Geographic Special Report (Issue), 1981; MS005.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Energy: Nuclear Energy Handbooks and Pamphlets, 1978 -- 1982; MS005.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Energy: A Plan for Action Edward Teller Commission on Critical Choices for Americans, 1975; MS005.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Energy: Uranium, Nonproliferation and Energy Security Steven J. Warnecke The Atlantic Institute for International Affairs, Paper No. 37, 1979; MS005.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Ephemera: Book Release Notices, Exhibit Material, Poems, Articles, 1954 -- 1986; MS005.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - European Hopes and Fears for Arms Control: A Message About Nervous Partners [US-Soviet Policy] Philipp Sonntag International Institute for Comparative Social Research, 1980; MS005.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Financial Data/Development and Construction of Nonproduction Reactors, 1953; MS005.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, List of Reviewers, 1984; MS005.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 2 Draft, 1980; MS005.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 3 Draft, 1982; MS005.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 5 Draft, 1982; MS005.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 6 Draft, 1982; MS005.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 7 Draft, 1982; MS005.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 8 Draft, 1983; MS005.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 1 Draft, 1985; MS005.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 2 Draft, 1985; MS005.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 3 Draft, 1985; MS005.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 4 Draft, 1985; MS005.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 8 Draft, 1983 -- 1985; MS005.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 9 Draft, 1985; MS005.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Hacker, Barton C.: Elements of Controversy, Ch. 10 Draft, 1985; MS005.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Halbritter's Arms Through the Ages [Cartoon]; Kurt Halbritter, 1977; MS005.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Health Effects of Ionizing Radiation Seminar/Global Radiation Victims Conferences, 1986 -- 1987; MS005.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - The Human Factor: Exhibit Information Pamphlets [Nova], 1987; MS005.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - The Hydrogen Bomb, Ch. 16 "The 'Castle' Tests"; J.R. Shepley and C. Blair, 1954; MS005.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - King, Eugene: Congressional Legislation, Correspondence, Legal Action, VA Decisions, and Medical Records Relating to Compensation for Injuries Due to Radiation Exposure, Folder 1, 1954 -- 1982; MS005.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - King, Eugene: Congressional Legislation, Correspondence, Legal Action, VA Decisions, and Medical Records Relating to Compensation for Injuries Due to Radiation Exposure, Folder 2, 1974 -- 1980; MS005.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - King, Eugene: Congressional Legislation, Correspondence, Legal Action, VA Decisions, and Medical Records Relating to Compensation for Injuries Due to Radiation Exposure, Folder 3, 1957 -- 1980; MS005.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - King, Eugene: Congressional Legislation, Correspondence, Legal Action, VA Decisions, and Medical Records Relating to Compensation for Injuries Due to Radiation Exposure, Folder 4, 1961 -- 1981; MS005.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Del Valle Vs. Cleland, Wallowitz, and Starbuck - Decision and Order, 1980; MS005.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Everett Vs. United States (No. C-2-79-127), Federal Supplement - Summary of Case, 1980; MS005.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Gott Vs. Cleland; Gott Vs. Nimmo - Preliminary Statements, Orders, and Opinions, 1981 -- 1982; MS005.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Honicker Vs. United States and Nuclear Regulatory Commission - Petition for a Writ of Certiorari; The Natural Rights Center, 1982; MS005.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Lombard Vs. United States, Smith, Ruff, Nuclear Regulatory Commission et al. - Complaint for Damages, 1980; MS005.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Legal: NAAV Vs. Department of Defense, Defense Nuclear Agency - Freedom of Information Act Complaint for Declaratory & Injunctive Relief, 1981; MS005.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Recognition of Radiation Exposure, 1980 -- 1986; MS005.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Silkwood Vs. Kerr-McGee - Depositions, Investigation Report, Articles, Newsletters, 1974 -- 1985; MS005.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Smitherman Vs. United States, VA, Department of Defense et al. - Original Complaint and Plaintiff's Opposition to the Defendants' Rule 12 Motions to Dismiss and to Strike Allegations of Complaint, 1985; MS005.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Supreme Court Decisions on Veterans Affairs Regulations, 1982 -- 1985; MS005.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Supreme Court/Federal Reporter (Cases Monaco, Jaffee, and Broudy); MA Laws on Toxin Exposure, 1979 -- 1981; MS005.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Veterans Affairs Regulations, 1982 -- 1985; MS005.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Legal: Veterans' Compensation Articles, 1984 -- 1985; MS005.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Birth Defects, 1985; MS005.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Effects of Radiation Exposure and Cancer, News Articles, 1959 -- 1980; MS005.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Effects of Radiation Exposure on People, News Articles and Pamphlets, 1979 -- 1986; MS005.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Effects of Radiation Exposure and Public Health, Articles and Reports, 1952 -- 1987; MS005.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Health Aspects of Nuclear Weapons Testing U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1964; MS005.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Hiroshima-Nagasaki Assessments, 1981 -- 1983; MS005.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Medical: NAAV Medical Study Forms, Jesuit Study, Rochester Study, 1954 -- 1981; MS005.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Research on Effects of Nuclear Radiation Exposure, Research Articles and Reports, 1976 -- 1986; MS005.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Research on Effects of Radiation Exposure, Research Articles and Reports, 1948 -- 1986; MS005.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Medical: Studies of Participants in Nuclear Tests Final Report, Medical Follow-Up Agency, National Research Council, 1985; MS005.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Medical: X-Ray and Radium Therapy and Radioisotopes Journal of the American Medical Association, 1959; MS005.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Medical: X-Rays, 1980 -- 1982; MS005.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - National Association of Atomic Veterans (NAAV), Legal Letters and Memos, 1979 -- 1984; MS005.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - National Association of Radiation Survivors (NARS), includes Board Minutes, Correspondence, Accounting [CARS: Haymarket Expenses], 1987; MS005.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters and Reports of Various Research, Political, and Government Groups, 1979 -- 1987; MS005.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Articles: The Boston Globe, 1986; MS005.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Detonations: Listing of Announced Detonations as of 1964, MS005.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Development: Book of Interviews with Exposed Victims and Families, 1984; MS005.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Energy: Articles and Safety, 1985 -- 1987; MS005.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Energy Industry: Articles, 1974 -- 1978; MS005.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Power Plants: Reports and Articles on Health Effects of East Coast Plants, 1977 -- 1987; MS005.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Testing Reviews: Shot Galileo, Shot Priscilla U.S. Defense Nuclear Agency, 1957; MS005.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Nuclear Waste: Articles and Pamphlets, 1981 -- 1986; MS005.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Operation Crossroads: Articles and Publicatios, 1946 -- 1986; MS005.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
    1946, 1980-1986.
  - Operation Crossroads: Bombs at Bikini: The Official Report of Operation Crossroads W.A. Shurcliff; Joint Task Force One, 1947; MS005.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Operation Doorstop - Yukka Flats Federal Civil Defense Administration, 1953; MS005.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Civilian Nuclear Power The 1967 Supplement to the 1962 Report to the President U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, MS005.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Radiological Safety Report to the Test Director (WT-1168) Lt.Col. Tom D. Collison; Armed Forces Special Weapons Project, DDC, 1955; MS005.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Reducing the Danger of Nuclear Weapons President Reagan, Current Policy No. 473 U.S. Department of State, 1983; MS005.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Report 1955 (DNA 6009F); Defense Nuclear Agency, 1981; MS005.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Shot Apple 2 (DNA 6012F) A Test of the Teapot Series 5 May 1955 Defense Nuclear Agency, 1981; MS005.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Shot Bee (DNA 6011F) A Test of the Teapot Series 22Mar 1955 Defense Nuclear Agency, 1981; MS005.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Shots ESS Through MET and Shot Zucchini (DNA 6013F) The Final Teapot Tests 23Mar-15May 1955 Defense Nuclear Agency, 1981; MS005.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Operation Teapot: Shots Wasp to Hornet (DNA 6010F) The First Five Teapot Tests 18Feb-12Mar 1955 Defense Nuclear Agency, 1981; MS005.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Organizations: Physicians, Clergy, Citizens, 1977 -- 1984; MS005.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Organizations: Physicians Groups Against Nuclear War, 1980 -- 1981; MS005.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Peace and Anti-Nuclear Groups, Folder 1, 1980 -- 1988; MS005.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Peace and Anti-Nuclear Groups, Folder 2, 1975 -- 1987; MS005.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Photograph: Kay Hinkle with Daughters Patti and Holly, 1984; MS005.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Plymouth: Health Reports on Effect of Pilgrim Power Plant, 1983 -- 1984; MS005.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Plymouth/Pilgrim and Seabrook Power Plants: Reports, Newsletters, and Articles, 1977 -- 1987; MS005.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Plymouth: Radiological Emergency Response Plan for Pilgrim Station Town of Plymouth, 1985; MS005.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Political: Newspaper Articles, 1984 -- 1986; MS005.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Policy: Celebrations Institute for Policy Studies, 1983; MS005.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Policy: Nuclear Fuels Policy Report of the Atlantic Council of the U.S. Nuclear Fuels Policy Working Group, 1977; MS005.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Policy: Up In Arms: A Common Cause Guide to Understanding Nuclear Arms Policy Sandra Sedacca; Common Cause, 1984; MS005.001.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - Progress Report and Preliminary 1981-83 Agenda United States Radiatio Policy Council, 1980; MS005.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Psychological Study: Betty Bahne, 1982 -- 1985; MS005.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Publications: Book Lists, 1984 -- 1987; MS005.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Publications: Local Radiation Concerns, Public Health, Misc., 1980 -- 1986; MS005.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Radiation Control Standards: Comments on Atomic Energy Control Board - Canada, 1984; MS005.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Radiation in Food, 1983 -- 1987; MS005.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Radiation Victims: Articles, Cartoons, Poems, Article on Loss of Army Personnel Records, 1974 -- 1987; MS005.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Radioactive Contamination of Certain Areas in the Pacific Ocean from Nuclear Tests [History II: 1957 Gov't Report] U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, MS005.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Report of the National Institutes of Health Ad Hoc Working Groupto Develop Radioepidemiological Tables U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 1985; MS005.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Report of the Task Force on Low-Level Radioactive Waste United States Radiation Policy Council, 1980; MS005.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Report of the Task Force on Occupational Radiation Exposure Regulations United States Radiation Policy Council, 1980; MS005.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Report of the Task Force on Radon in Structures United States Radiation Policy Council, 1980; MS005.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Science and Siberia: The Soviet Union Today and Tomorrow Guri Marchuk; Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, 1983; MS005.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Secrecy in Government/Freedom of Information Act, 1982 -- 1986; MS005.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Some Effects of Ionizing Radiation on Human Beings Ed. by E.P. Cronkite; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1956; MS005.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - South Pacific: Articles, 1982 -- 1987; MS005.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Three Mile Island, 1983 -- 1987; MS005.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - U.S.-Soviet Policy: Articles, 1980 -- 1985; MS005.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Veterans Benefits: Publications, 1980 -- 1981; MS005.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - Veterans Groups: NARS, DAV, NAAV, Newsletters, Information Letters, 1979 -- 1987; MS005.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Victims Groups, 1979 -- 1984; MS005.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - War Heads: Cartoonists Draw the Line Ed. by Steven Heller; The Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign, 1983; MS005.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Waste Disposal: Hazardous Waste (GAO/RCED-86-76) Federal Agencies Slow to Comply with Regulatory Requirements U.S. General Accounting Office, 1986; MS005.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Waste Disposal: Nuclear Waste (GAO/RCED-86-90) Department of Energy's Transuranic Waste Disposal Plan Needs Revision U.S. General Accounting Office, 1986; MS005.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Workmen's Compensatio: Articles, Cases, Studies in Workmen's Compensation and Radiation Injury Vol. V and VI, 1963 -- 1972; MS005.001.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - Advisory Committee on Human Radiation Experiments: Final Report, 1995; MS005.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    Release date copy.
  - Advisory Committee on Human Radiation Experiments: Final Report Supplemental Volume 1, 1995; MS005.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Advisory Committee on Human Radiation Experiments: Final Report Supplemental Volume 2, 1995; MS005.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Advisory Committee on Human Radiation Experiments: Final Report Supplemental Volume 2a, 1995; MS005.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Advisory Committee on Human Radiation Experiments: Attachments, 1995; MS005.001.005.00005 (Box 5)